#### **YANCONG YIN**

New York, NY 10019 | (646) 236-1157 | agathayin.sh@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://agathayin15.wixsite.com/mysite/projects

# **SUMMARY**

Highly self-motivated professional committed to pursuing a long-term career in digital design. Combined expertise in graphic design and front-end programming that follow through with projects from concept to completion. Outstanding problem-solving capabilities and ability to work with teams.

#### **EDUCATION**

The New School, New York

Master of Arts, Media Studies

GPA 3.92/4.0

Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

Selected Coursework

Graphic and Web Design, Interactive Design, UX Research, Data Analysis and Visualization

Communication University of China, Beijing

Bachelor of Arts, Dutch Language and Literature

GPA 3.34/4.0

July 2011 - July 2015

July 2012 - July 2014

Selected Coursework

Dutch Linguistics, Politics, Economy and Culture of the Netherlands and Belgium News Writing and Interview Skills, New Media Skills, Social Media Theory

# **EXPERIENCE**

Minor: Journalism

# The Artists Forum, New York City

Graphic and Web Design intern

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Analyze and amend website information structure. The new structure analysis and prototype sketch assists planning for the website innovation and future work allocation.
- Optimize website responsibility on mobile devices. Resolve the scale errors on small screens and redesign user experience on tablets and phones.
- Design and proofread all printings such as brochure and postcard for non-profit film festival.

#### **51 Offer**, Shanghai

Website Editor

July 2015 - Aug 2016

- Column planning including graphic design and content. This column served as the monthly special and it attracted extra 30% visits.
- Strategized content selection and editing according to customer behavior report which was based on Google Analytics data and social media feedback.
- Collaborated with other teams and supported for the website design.

# **Fabang Information,** Shanghai

Social Media Intern

July 2014 - Sep 2014

- Analyzed social media content performance daily, and identified top performing and underperforming content.
- Media support. Edited videos and created graphic design according to content planning.

# **CUC Students' Association Union, Beijing**

University Magazine Editor

Aug 2011 - May 2015

- Developed artwork and layout for magazine with Adobe Indesign and other tools.
- Read and edited content written by invited guest authors. Proofreaded and checked upon texts and images to avoid mistakes on printing.

Teaching Assistant Sep 2016 - Aug 2017

• English Language tutoring and reading material revision.

• Assisted social media assistant with creating content about language learning

#### **SELECTED ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Graphic design gallery: <a href="https://agathayin15.wixsite.com/mysite/projects">https://agathayin15.wixsite.com/mysite/projects</a>

Some design projects including branding challenge and others

Forum-like web design: <a href="http://www.livelanguage.com/yiny/index.html">http://www.livelanguage.com/yiny/index.html</a>

a clean and cozy forum-like website using JavaScript coding and JQuery to increase interactions

P5.js Data Visualization: <a href="http://agathayin.henryhu.net/fake-news/index.html">http://agathayin.henryhu.net/fake-news/index.html</a>

Fake news vs fact-checking data visualization. Use JavaScript for data mining and P5.js for visualization.

Javascript storytelling: choice tree: <a href="http://agathayin.henryhu.net/LC/index.html">http://agathayin.henryhu.net/LC/index.html</a>

Interactive website game made by JavaScript. Based on the existing game. Build a system to organize several stories into the choice tree and display the content according to interactions

Real-time clock without hands challenge: <a href="http://agathayin.henryhu.net/clock/myCanvas/index.html">http://agathayin.henryhu.net/clock/myCanvas/index.html</a>
Express time with imagination and no numbers and no clock hands. The project shows real time.

**Bootstrap practice: Redesign website:** <a href="http://agathayin.henryhu.net/theartistsforum/index.htm">http://agathayin.henryhu.net/theartistsforum/index.htm</a> Use Bootstrap to create new blog-like interface for a current website with better responsibility.

### **SKILLS**

#### **Graphic Design:**

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

Adobe XD (prototype)

Adobe Premiere (video)  $\star\star\star\star$ Figma  $\star\star\star\star$ 

# Back-End Development:

Node.js ★★★☆ Wordpress ★★★★

# Front-End Development:

HTML  $\star\star\star\star\star$ CSS  $\star\star\star\star\star$ JavaScript  $\star\star\star\star\star$ JQuery  $\star\star\star\star\star$ D3.js  $\star\star\star\star\star$ P5.js  $\star\star\star\star\star$ Bootstrap  $\star\star\star\star\star$ 

#### Others:

Bigquery
Tableau

MS Word

MS Excel

MS PowerPoint

★★☆

★★★★

### Language:

Chinese (Mandarin)  $\star\star\star\star\star$ English  $\star\star\star\star$ Dutch  $\star\star\star\star$